Guide to the Editta Sherman Photographs 1940-1995 (bulk, undated) PR 322
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. The Melisande Sherman Collection, 1940-1956 (bulk, undated); 4.83 Linear feet
  - Matted & Other Oversize
    - Elsa Maxwell, Undated (Drawer FF2)
    - Julie Newmar, Undated (Drawer FF2)
    - Julie Newmar, Undated (Drawer FF2)
    - Eugene Ormandy, Undated (Drawer FF2)
    - Susan Strasberg (color, signed), Undated (Drawer FF2)
    - Susan Strasberg, Undated (Drawer FF2)
    - Efrem Zimbalist, Undated (Drawer FF2)
    - Unidentified [man with a moustache], Undated (Drawer FF2)
- Series III. The Children of Lloyd Sherman Collection, 1945-1965 (bulk, undated); 4.83 Linear feet
  The photographs in this series were a gift in July 2016 of the children of Lloyd Sherman, one of Editta Sherman's sons: Jason Sherman, Brendan Sherman, Caleb Sherman, Jessica Petraglia, and Justin Sherman. (Credit line: Gift of the children of Lloyd R. Sherman.)
  - 8 x 10 Photographs
    - Maurice Abravanel, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - [Stanley C. Allyn] National Cash Register (3 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
      Also includes a photo of an unidentified person in the sleeve with the Allyn photos.
    - Don Ameche, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Ray Bolger (2 photos/one pose), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - John Carradine (3 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Patricia Collinge, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Noel Coward (2 photos/2 poses, one signed), 1952, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
      Includes an acknowledgement from Coward regarding Sherman's support of the American Theater Wing.
    - Clifford Curzon (7 photos/6 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Laraine Day, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
      Includes a second photo, of an unidentified Benton & Bowers executive, in the photo sleeve.
    - Robert (or Charles?) Evans (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
      The photos are noted as "Bob Evans" on the reverse, but the code assigned to them by the family indicates Charles (EvansC2320401 and 0501).
    - Douglas Fairbanks, Jr., Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Henry Fonda & Barbara Bel Geddes (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Henry Fonda & Susan Strasberg, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Massimo Freccia (3 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Donald Harrington (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Fernando Lamas (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Captain Lane (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Al Lewis, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Vincent Lopez (5 photos/4 poses, one signed), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Leopold Mannes, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Neil McNeil, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Kay Medford (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Melody, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Robert Merrill, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Arnold Moss, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Lyn Murray (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Lord Boyd Orr, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Princess Juanita [Cherokee Nation?] (4 photos/4 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Rodger Pryor, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Anthony Quinn, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Chief Rising Sun / Rising Star, Cherokee Indian (2 photos/one pose, one signed), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Walter Bedell Smith (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - General Captain Smith, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Tilda Swinton (3 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Deems Taylor, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Rudy Vallee (2 photos/duplicate), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Diana Van der Vlis, Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Carl Van Doren (3 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Herman Wouk (7 photos/7 poses, one inscribed), Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Gig Young [and Elizabeth Montgomery], Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Unidentified [man in a feather headdress / Cherokee Nation?], Undates (Offsite-box 3)
    - Unidentified [man in a feather headdress / Cherokee Nation?], Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Unidentified [man in a feather headdress / Cherokee Nation?], Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - Unidentified [boy in a feather headdress / Cherokee Nation?], Undated (Offsite-box 3)
    - [Unidentified. Group of Four Men, Band?], 1960s? (Offsite-box 3)
      Large format negative, color.
  - 11 x 14 Photographs
    - Stanley C. Allyn, Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Don Ameche (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Lee Barker (3 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Ray Bolger, 1950 (Offsite-box 6)
    - John Carradine (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - June Carter Cash (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Clifford Curzon (15 photos/12 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
      Includes portraits of Curzon, one of Curzon and a woman, and images of Curzon on stage at a piano, including with George Szell.
    - Laraine Day (3 photos/2 poses), 1952, Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Laraine Day & Leo Durocher (2 photos/2 poses), 1960, Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Leo Durocher (2 photos/2 poses, one signed), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - J.H.S. Ellis, Undated (Offsite-box 6)
      Includes ElliJ3940101.
    - Charles Evans (3 photos/3 poses, one signed), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Robert Evans (7 photos/7 poses), 1955, Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Douglas Fairbanks, Jr., Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Betty Fields, Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Henry Fonda (2 photos/one pose, one signed), 1945 (Offsite-box 6)
    - Massimo Freccia (4 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Huntington Hartford (3 photos/2 poses, one signed), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Fernando Lamas (7 photos/7 poses, 4 signed), 1960, 1965, Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Captain Lane (2 photos/one pose, one signed), 1948 (Offsite-box 6)
    - Richard Leacock (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Vincent Lopez (2 photos/one pose), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Neil McNeil (3 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Moondog (2 photos/2 poses, one signed), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Frank Morgan (3 photos/3 poses, one signed, one inscribed), 1945, Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - LeRoy Neiman (3 photos/3 poses, two autographed, one signed), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Lord Boyd Orr (3 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Louis Persinger (4 photos/4 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Joseph Picone, Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Rodger Pryor (6 photos/6 poses) (Offsite-box 6)
    - Anthony Quinn (3 photos/2 poses), 1959 (Offsite-box 6)
    - Red Wing Cherokee Tribe [woman with beads] (2 photos/one pose), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Walter Bedell Smith (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Deems Taylor, Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Rudy Vallee (3 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Diana Van der Vlis (3 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Carl Van Doren, Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Ruth Warrick (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Herman Wouk and Family (12 photos/9 poses, one signed, one signed and autographed), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
      Includes portraits of Wouk, his wife Sarah, and their family.
    - Gig Young (2 photos/one pose), Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Unidentified [man with ring], Undated (Offsite-box 6)
    - Unidentified [man with a pencil], Undated (Offsite-box 6)
  - 16 x 20 Photographs
    - Maurice Abravanel, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Edna Best, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Ray Bolger, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Leo Durocher, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Clifford Curzon [and wife?], Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Leo Durocher, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Leo Durocher & Larine Day, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - J. H. S. Ellis, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Robert Evans (3 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 7)
      One photo is of Robert, though family coded it as of Charles Evans (EvanC2320102).
    - Douglas Fairbanks, Jr., Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Henry Fonda (3 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Raymond Fosdick (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Massimo Freccia (2 photos/2 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Donald Harrington, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Leopold Mannes (2 photos/one pose), Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Ray Middleton, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - LeRoy Neiman (autographed), Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Robert Paine, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Rodger Pryor, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Carlos Salzedo, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Walter Bedell Smith, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Walter B. Smith[?], Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Tilda Swinton (3 photos/3 poses), Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Deems Taylor, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Mark Van Doren, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Herman Wouk (autographed), Undated (Offsite-box 7)
    - Gig Young & Elizabeth Montgomery, Undated (Offsite-box 7)
  - Matted & Other Oversize
    - Clifford Curzon (color, signed), Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - Laraine Day, Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - Henry Fonda & Susan Strasberg (color, signed), Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - Huntington Hartford, Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - Fernando Lamas, Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - Elizabeth Montgomery, Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - LeRoy Neiman (signed, autographed), Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - Rudy Vallee, Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - Verushka Von Lehndorff (signed), Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - Verushka von Lehndorff, Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - Verushka von Lehndorff (inscribed and signed, color), Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - Verushka von Lehndorff (signed), Undated (Drawer FF3)
    - Herman Wouk & Family (color, signed, autographed), Undated (Drawer FF3)